Marcus Loo Vergara

Trondheim, Norway

☎ NO +47 411 78 583 • @ marcus.loo.vergara@gmail.com • ♦ bitsauce.github.io

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Senior student at the Norwegian University of Science and Technology working towards a master's degree in Computer Science. Specializing in computer graphics and computer vision, with a recent focus on deep learning. Expecting graduation June 2019. Self-motivated, quick learner, and enjoy helping others.

• C/C++

OptiX & CUDA

• OpenGL & GLSL

Pvthon

• Deep Learning

Keras, PyTorch & TensorFlow

TCP & UDP

• React Native

• JavaScript, HTML & CSS

EDUCATION

Norwegian University of Science and Technology, Trondheim, Norway Master of Science in Computer Science

• Specializing in computer graphics, computer vision, and deep learning

Aug 2013 - Expected Jun 2019

GPA: 3.00

University of California, San Diego, San Diego, USA

Master of Science in Computer Science

• Studied at UC San Diego for a year

Oct 2017 - Jun 2018

GPA: 3.49

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Graphics Software Engineering Intern, Sony PlayStation

Internship at PlayStation's Developer Technology Group (DTG)

Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

- Created a performance analysis tool for the PlayStation 4TM that visualizes certain aspects of the performance of the GPU; with the intention of having such a tool be used by DTG to more quickly find and suggest improvements to their customers
- Implemented the metallic workflow a physically-based shading technique into a rendering engine that runs on the PlayStation 4^{TM}
- Trained a simple autoencoder to generate metallic, roughness and ambient occlusion textures from albedo and normal maps only
- Exposure to low-level programming for specialized hardware
- Gained experience in teamwork and good coding practices

Software Developer, Grabster

Jul 2017 – Aug 2017

Summer job assisting a start-up in app development

- Grabster is a sharing economy platform based on buying and selling food between individuals
- Implemented and tested screen navigation and backend functionality for the Android app
- Gained experience in using *React Native* and *Node.js*

Teaching Assistant, Norwegian University of Science and Technology On-campus part-time job assisting students

Aug 2015 – May 2017

- Support and advising in solving theoretical and practical questions
- Graded assignments
- Assigned subjects:
 - Jan 2019 May 2019: Computer vision and deep learning
 - Jan 2016 May 2017: Procedural and object-oriented programming (C++)
 - Aug 2015 Dec 2015: Computers and Digital Design (Assembly programming)

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Reinforcement Learning for Autonomous Vehicles, Thesis

Sep 2019 - Present

Used state-of-the-art deep reinforcement learning methods to teach a simulated car to drive itself in OpenAl's *CarRacing-v0* environment, achieving top results

- Implemented current deep reinforcement learning baseline, *Proximal Policy Optimization*, with Python and TensorFlow
- Substantially decreased training time by scaling the output mean of each action's Gaussian distributions to their respective limits
- Planning to train the same agent in CARLA a car simulator running in Unreal Engine 4
- Video of results: https://youtu.be/8X_LSy4TF84

OptiX Soft Shadows, CSE 274 Course project

Mar 2018

Used NVIDIA's OptiX ray tracer to implement Axis-Aligned Filtering for Interactive Sampled Soft Shadows

- Provided a fundamental understanding of the use of frequency analysis in ray tracing
- Achieved interactive framerates of about 5-30 FPS on a Nvidia GTX 970

Deep Learning Projects, Course projects

May 2017 - Jun 2018

Summary of some deep learning projects and paper implementations

- Implemented a Mask R-CNN based model to detect human joints in images of people
- Experimented with convolutional architectures *PointNet* and *PointNet++* to segment stem and leaf points in point scans of plants with some scans having more than a million points
- Implemented a recurrent LSTM model to automatically generate captions for images
- Trained a Faster R-CNN model to identify and locate cars in images taken on the road

Game Engine Programming, Side-project

2010 - Present

Writing a game engine from scratch in C++

- Ongoing side-project since 2010
- Uses OpenGL and Simple DirectMedia Library to render to the screen
- Intended to serve as a mode of learning the inner-workings of game engines
- Developed alongside the an infinite procedurally generated sandbox game
 - See my homepage, bitsauce.github.io, for more information about these and other projects

CAMPUS ACTIVITIES

Abakus GameDev, Norwegian University of Science and Technology

Co-founder and leader of student organization *Abakus GameDev* – a student organization for people who enjoy making games, discussing their development, design, and the industry in general

- Responsible for creating a socket-based framework that was used for AI competitions
- Participates in meetings, discussing workshop ideas and advertising
- Held a presentation on reinforcement learning for games